<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Getting CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engine and Integration Options</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/engine_integration_options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/engine_integration_options/</guid><description>The Core Rule Set can be run using a compatible WAF engine. The CRS can also be used via a number of services which feature CRS integration, such as cloud and CDN-based WAF offerings.
Compatible WAF Engines ModSecurity ModSecurity comes in two flavours: ModSecurity v2 and ModSecurity v3 (aka libmodsecurity).
Existing CRS Integrations: Cloud and CDN Offerings AWS WAF Microsoft Azure WAF</description></item><item><title>OWASP CRS Quickstart</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/quickstart/</guid><description>Welcome to the OWASP Core RuleSet (CRS) quickstart guide. We will attempt to get you up and running with CRS as quick as possible. This guide assumes ModSecurity is already working. If you are unsure see the extended install page. Otherwise, lets jump in.
You&amp;rsquo;ll first need to download the ruleset. Using a browser (or equivalent) visit the following URL:
wget https://github.com/coreruleset/coreruleset/archive/master.zip Once this is installed extract it somewhere well known on your server.</description></item><item><title>Installing CoreRuleSet</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/install/</guid><description>If you need mode information than the one in the quickstart guide, here we extend with additional details so keep reading.
Below you should find all the information you need to properly install CRS. If you are having problems feel free to reach out to our Google Group, or our Slack Channel. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have access yet, get your invite here.
Prerequisites Installing the CRS isn&amp;rsquo;t very hard but it does have one major requirement, ModSecurity.</description></item></channel></rss>