<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Getting CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engine and Integration Options</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/engine_integration_options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/engine_integration_options/</guid><description>The Core Rule Set runs on WAF engines that are compatible with a subset of ModSecurity&amp;rsquo;s SecLang configuration language. There are several options outside of ModSecurity itself, namely cloud offerings and content delivery network (CDN) services. There is also an open-source alternative to ModSecurity in the form of the new Coraza WAF engine.
Compatible Free and Open-Source WAF Engines ModSecurity v2 ModSecurity v2, originally a security module for the Apache web server, is the reference implementation for CRS.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start Guide</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/quick_start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/quick_start/</guid><description>This quick start guide aims to get a CRS installation up and running as quickly as possible. This guide assumes that ModSecurity is already present and working. If unsure then refer to the extended install page for full details.
Downloading the Rule Set The first step is to download the Core Rule Set itself. The CRS project strongly recommends using a supported version.
Official CRS releases can be found at the following URL: https://github.</description></item><item><title>Extended Install</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/deployment/install/</guid><description>All the information needed to properly install CRS is presented on this page. The installation concepts are expanded upon and presented in more detail than the quick start guide.
Contact Us To contact the CRS project with questions or problems, reach out via the project&amp;rsquo;s Google group or Slack channel (for Slack channel access, use this link to get an invite).
Prerequisites Installing the CRS isn&amp;rsquo;t very difficult but does have one major requirement: a compatible engine.</description></item></channel></rss>