<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Creating Rules on Core Rule Set Documentation</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/</link><description>Recent content in Creating Rules on Core Rule Set Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rule IDs</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/ruleid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/ruleid/</guid><description>Why do rule IDs matter? Each rule added to a ModSecurity instance must have a unique ID (in recent versions of modsec). As a result of this it is important that IDs be generated in a preplanned way such that they don't overlap with other rules. This becomes particularly important when it comes to rulesets, like OWASP CRS. Because CRS can be used with other rule sets (in fact it is designed to be used with the Trustwave commercial rules, for instance) it is important that no two rulesets have overlapping ID ranges.</description></item><item><title>Testing the Rule Set</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/testing/</guid><description>Shipped with the ruleset are a number of different tools. One of these tools are the regression testing framework for OWASP CRS. For testing we use WTF (WAF Testing Framework). This framework allows us to specify HTTP requests via a YAML file. Each modification to CRS must pass the existing tests in order to be accepted. Additionally, if you are planning to add a rule, you should ensure that a test has been written.</description></item><item><title>Rules</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/rules/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s In The Rules | REQUEST-900-EXCLUSION-RULES-BEFORE-CRS.conf.example | Configuration Path: rules/REQUEST-900-EXCLUSION-RULES-BEFORE-CRS.conf.example | This file is used to add LOCAL exceptions for your site. Often in this file we would see rules that short-circuit inspection and allow certain transactions to skip through inspection. Example: SecRule REMOTE_ADDR &amp;quot;@ipMatch 192.168.1.100&amp;quot; &amp;quot;phase:1,id:'981033',t:none,nolog,pass,ctl:ruleEngine=Off&amp;quot;| | REQUEST-901-INITIALIZATION.conf | TODO | | REQUEST-903.9001-DRUPAL-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9002-WORDPRESS-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9003-NEXTCLOUD-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9004-DOKUWIKI-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9005-CPANEL-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9006-XENFORO-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf | TODO |
REQUEST-901-INITIALIZATION.conf TODO
REQUEST-903.9001-DRUPAL-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9002-WORDPRESS-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9003-NEXTCLOUD-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9004-DOKUWIKI-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9005-CPANEL-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf REQUEST-903.9006-XENFORO-EXCLUSION-RULES.conf TODO</description></item><item><title>Making</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/creating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/creating/</guid><description>Making Rules The Basic Synatax A SecRule is a directive like any other understood by ModSecurity. The difference is that this directive is way more powerful in what it is capable of representing. Generally, a SecRule is made up of 4 parts:
Variables - Instructs ModSecurity where to look (sometimes called Targets) Operators - Instructs ModSecurity when to trigger a match Transformations - Instructs ModSecurity how it should normalize variable data Actions - Instructs ModSecurity what to do if a rule matches The structure of the rule is as follows:</description></item><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://coreruleset.github.io/documentation/rules/metadata/</guid><description>OWASP CRS Metadata OWASP CRS 3.x includes several pieces of metadata within rules. Not every rule features all metadata but it is a continuing project where possible to update this information to the best possible level. If you see a rule without a piece of metadata that you think is warranted please open either an issue or a pull request.
Tags about standards We try our best to outline information about the vulnerability when each rule triggers.</description></item></channel></rss>