<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuring the CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</title><link>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/</link><description>Recent content in Configuring the CRS on Core Rule Set Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anomaly Scoring Mode</title><link>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/anomaly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/anomaly/</guid><description>From version 3.0 onwards, Anomaly Scoring is the default detection mode. Traditional detection mode is discouraged.
Within the csr-setup.conf.example you can control the following related CRS items:
Anomaly Scoring Severity Levels Anomaly Scoring Threshold Levels (Blocking) Enable/Disable Blocking Choose the default logging actions and much more! Anomaly Scoring Mode Within anomaly scoring mode we are implementing the concept of Collaborative Detection and Delayed Blocking. This is to say that we have changed the rules logic by decoupling the inspection/detection from the blocking functionality.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/crs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/crs/</guid><description>Configuring OWASP CRS TODO</description></item><item><title>Adding Exceptions and Tuning CRS</title><link>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/exceptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fzipi.github.io/coreruleset-documentation/configuring/exceptions/</guid><description>Modifying Rules OWASP Core Rule Set (CRS) as a rule set for ModSecurity has no context into what your web application is doing and how it is designed. As a result, often legitimate requests might seem to CRS to be attacks. This term is often called a False Positive. While the CRS team does its best to prevent these from happening, they are somewhat inevitable due to the blacklist nature of the rules.</description></item></channel></rss>